はあ…
おい バイト！ 表 頼む！
は～い！
そんなこと言ってない！
言ったではないか 休憩を
挟みながらの方が効率的だとか
Hey, part-timer!
あんたこそ ちょっと歩く度に
小休止が必要だとか…
Take care of the front.
Okay!
あれは
機関の追跡から逃れるためだ
Stop saying that.
誰も追いかけてこないっつうの
You said it would be
岡部 倫太郎！
うん？
be more efficient if we took breaks...
何これ？
フン… 聞きたいか？
Well, you're the one who needs to rest
本来であれば 重要機密事項のため
every few steps.
We need to hide from Organization pursuit.
簡単に教えるわけには
いかないところだが…
No one's chasing us.
ああ～ もう！
長くなるんなら 一回 下ろすわ…
Okabe Rintarou!
What's this?
耐えろ 助手！
You want to know?
だったら もったいぶってないで
ちゃっちゃと言いなさいよ！
Normally, it would be top-secret,
バカを言うな 最重要アイテムだぞ
and I wouldn't be able to just tell you.
ここで もったいつけずして
どこで もったいつけるのだ
If you're going to take a while, then put it down!
もしかして IBN5100？
Endure, assistant.
Then stop making it into a big deal,
and just tell her!
なっ！ バレてしまったではないか
クリスティーナ！
Don't be stupid.
どこにあったの？
This item is of the utmost importance.
柳林神社に奉納されていたのを
If we don't make a big deal out of it here,
この神に選ばれし
マッドサイエンティストである…
then where should we
make a big deal out of it?
Is it an IBN 5100?
だから
長くなるなら下ろすと言ってる…
She found out, Christina!
牧瀬 紅莉栖
Where'd you find one?
えっ？ あっ はい
It was kept in Yanabayashi Shrine,
この人は？
where I, the mad scientist chosen by God...
ブラウン管工房の… バイト…
I said put it down!
えっ？ あ あの…
Makise Kurisu...
Y-Yes.
Who is this?
あっ…
A part-timer at the CRT TV Workshop...
おい バイト！
なに 油 売ってんだ
Um...
ううっ…
なんで にらまれたわけ？
Hey! Part-timer!
お前の目つきが悪いからだろう
What are you doing, talking on the job?
なっ…！
Why was she glaring at me?
Because you look like a thug.
Starmine Rendezvous
本当に大きいねえ
It really is big!
虎さんの敷物みたいだねえ
アハハ…
It's like a tiger rug!
オホ～！ お布団みたい
It's like a futon.
まゆ氏が 僕のシャツの上に…
Mayushii is lying on my shirt.
胸が熱くなる光景
The sight warms my heart!
よ～し ゆっくり 下ろせ
分かってるわよ
Okay, let it down slowly.
紅莉栖ちゃん！
I know.
Kurisu-chan!
ごめんなさいね
また 急に来ちゃった
Sorry to come by so suddenly again.
ううん いつ来てもいいんだよ
You can come whenever you want.
ラボメンなんだから
You're a lab member.
昨日までは 二度と来ないと
言っていたのだがな
Yesterday, she was saying
she'd never come back.
現金なヤツだ
You change your mind quite easily, don't you?
別に 来たくて来たわけじゃない
I'm not here because I want to be!
あんたが
手伝えって言うからでしょ
You asked me for help.
ええ？ 紅莉栖ちゃん
やっぱり 来たくないの？
So you don't want to come here?
えっ？ ああ いや そうじゃないの
ここが嫌ってことじゃなくて…
No, that isn't it.
It's not that I don't like this place...
で その箱は 何よ？
So what's in the box?
フッ… 聞きたいか？
本来であれば…
You want to know?
Normally, it would be...
IBN5100
An IBN 5100.
マジ？ すげえよ！
さすが オカリン！
Seriously? Wow!
Way to go, Okarin!
僕たちにできないことを
平然と やってのける
He does all the things an Okarin can!
そこに しびれる
憧れないけどね
And that's why we love him—
I don't admire him, though.
えっ？
あっ… オホン！
とにかく 起動させてみるわよ
A-Anyway, boot it up!
見つけられたのは
まゆしぃのおかげなんだよ
We found it thanks to Mayushii.
ああ 今回ばかりは お手柄だ
Yeah.
The glory for this goes to you.
エヘヘヘ
ついた
It turned on.
これで あのプログラムコードが
解析できるんだな？
Now you can analyze that program code, right?
そんな簡単じゃないって
It's not that simple...
こいつの使い方 分からないし
I don't know how to use this.
ネット環境がない
時代のものだから
It predates the internet,
つないで
どうこうできるもんでもないし
so I can't hook it up to anything.
とりあえず
これだけ パーツが必要
For now, I'll need these parts.
だそうだ 頼んだぞ 助手
You heard the man.
Take care of it, assistant.
当然のような顔で言うの
やめてほしいんだが
I'd like you to stop talking to me like that.
助手だろ
ち･が･う！
You're my assistant.
No, I'm not!
オカリン 行ってよ
Okarin, you go.
牧瀬氏
アキバ 詳しくないだろうし
Miss Makise probably doesn't know Akiba.
しかたがない… まゆり 行くぞ！
Very well.
Mayuri, let's go!
まゆしぃは 紅莉栖ちゃんに
ラボを好きになってもらえるよう
Mayushii will do her best to show
Kurisu-chan around the lab,
一生懸命 案内するので
お留守番しています
so she'll like it!
So, I'll stay here.
クリスティーナ 貴様…！
Christina, you...
まさか まゆりも その色香に…
かけとらんわ！
You couldn't have entrapped Mayuri
with your wiles, as well—
I did no such thing!
牧瀬氏が まゆ氏を…
Miss Makise seducing Mayuri...
百合展開 キター
Yuri is in the air...
想像するな HENTAI！
Don't imagine that, pervert!
女の子同士って いいよね
It's nice for girls to be together, isn't it?
そ それより 早く 案内して？
うん！
Anyway, why don't you show me around?
Okay!
じゃあ まず 奥の
シャワールームから紹介しま～す
We'll start with the shower room.
えっ？ シャワーもあるんだ
It has a shower...
うん でも お湯 ずっと出してると
But sometimes, if you use it for too long,
the water gets cold. So be careful!
たまに お水になっちゃうから
注意してね
ねえ もしかして
まゆりさんも使ったりするの？
You use this sometimes?
うん たまに
Yeah, once in a while.
あっ… お願い 二度と ここでは
シャワーを浴びないって約束して
Please promise me you'll never
use the shower here again!
あまりに危険よ！
こっちを見るな
It's too dangerous!
Don't look at me.
自殺行為っていうか…
It's suicide.
Actually, what are you doing here anyway?
そもそも
なぜ あなたが ここにいるの？
何か 脅迫されて
Did he threaten or blackmail
無理やり メンバーに
させられてるんじゃないの？
you into becoming a member, against your will?
まゆしぃは オカリンの人質なので
Mayushii is Okarin's hostage.
あっ…
警察に電話した方がよさそうね
あっ… 待て！
I should call the police.
Wait!
今 ｢人質｣って言ったでしょ
動かぬ証拠
She just said she was your hostage.
That's real evidence.
違うよ
Nope.
まゆしぃは
自分で人質になったのです
Mayushii became a hostage herself!
えっ？ どういうこと？
What does that mean?
フッ… 行ってくる
I'm going.
いってらっしゃ～い！
Bye!
あっ…
確か これで代用できたはずだが…
This should work as a replacement,
I'm pretty sure...
うい～っす！
Yo!
IBN5100は使えそう？
Think you'll be able to use that IBN 5100?
し～っ！
こんな所で その名前を口にするな
Don't say that name here!
パーツ集め… 手伝おうか？
Collecting parts?
Want some help?
まさか バイト戦士が
こんなに パソコンに詳しいとはな
I didn't expect a part-time warrior
to be so knowledgeable about PCs.
うん IBNのこと 詳しい人と
知り合いだったから
I once knew someone who
understood a lot about IBNs.
なっ…！ 本当か？
なら 連絡を取ってもらいたい！
Really?
I'd like you to put me in touch with them!
無理
It's impossible.
なっ… 拒否すれば お前は
この世の地獄を見ることになる
If you refuse, you'll experience the
worst hell this world has to offer!
無理なものは無理
命が惜しくないのか！
I said it's impossible.
Don't you value your life?
だって
死んじゃったんだもん その人
He's dead.
何年も前に
He died years ago.
すまん
I'm sorry.
こっちこそ ごめんね さっき…
No, I apologize for earlier.
Did my assistant do something to you?
ウチの助手が 何か したのか？
Nothing.
ううん 何も
先に にらみつけたとか…
Like maybe she glared at you first...
おお…
鼻で笑ったりしたのだろう？
I know, she snorted at you!
違うよ 彼女は何もしてない
No.
She hasn't done anything.
えっ それじゃあ…
Then...
まだ 彼女は…
She doesn't know anything yet.
何も知らない
うん？
But be wary of her.
でも 気を付けて 牧瀬 紅莉栖には
どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?
あっ！
爆撃！
Bombs?
うん？ 花火の中継だろう
They're broadcasting the fireworks.
確か 今日だからな
Those are today, I think.
花火？ 花火…
Fireworks... Fireworks...
聞いたことがある！
I've heard of those!
えっ 見たことないのか？
You've never seen any?
どこ？ どっち？
Where are they? Which way?
その通りを抜け
川の方まで行けば見えるはずだ
Go out that way, toward the river,
and you should be able to see them.
ありがとう！
Thanks!
ああっ…
メアド 教えて！
Tell me your mail address.
お祭り？
A festival?
花火大会だよ
Fireworks!
花火か…
Fireworks, huh?
Do you want to go?
行きたいの？
えっ？ べ 別に…
Not really...
あっ オカリン！
Okarin!
トゥットゥルー！
帰りか？
うん
Heading home?
パーツは見つかったの？
ここに 全部 そろっている
Did you find the parts?
I've got them all right here.
そう… じゃあ これから
いろいろ 試してみるわけね
I see...
So you're going to start trying things.
興味があるか？
うん？
Interested?
あるのだな
You are, aren't you?
あ～ もう！ 少しだけね
Just a little, all right?
でも ＳＥＲＮの陰謀とかいう
But I'm not interested
荒唐無稽なものに対する
興味じゃない
in that SERN conspiracy nonsense.
あくまで 事実を確かめたいだけ
I just want to know the truth.
ごめんなさい
なになに？
I'm sorry.
What? What?
私 やっぱり
一度 ラボラトリーに戻る
I'm heading back to the lab.
そっか
じゃあ まゆしぃは帰ります
I see.
Then Mayushii is going home.
うん
フフッ… あっ…
Okay.
紅莉栖ちゃん
うん？
Kurisu-chan?
Yes?
また 来てくれるよね？
You'll come back, right?
うん アメリカ 帰るまでは
メンバーだものね
Yeah.
I'm a member until I return to America.
うん！
Yeah!
じゃあね～！
Bye!
何を聞いているのだ？
What was that?
助手なのだから
ラボに来るのは当然だろう
You're my assistant.
Of course you're going to the lab.
はあ…
あんたたち 幼なじみですってね
同じ環境で育ちながら
She said you're childhood friends.
How did you grow up
どうして こう
社会性がなくなっちゃったんだか
in the same environment,
and end up this socially awkward?
まゆりは 昔から
変わったところがあったからな
Mayuri's always been a bit of a weird one...
あなたに言ってるの！
I was talking to you!
Part-Time Warrior
First Message
More than I imagined!
Fireworks are great!
First Message.
…｢想像以上！
凄いね 花火～～！｣
More than I imagined!
Fireworks are great!
フッ…
ふ～ん あれっきり 一度も…
It never worked after that, huh?
あっ… これ 借りるわよ
I'm borrowing this.
はあ… やっぱり 落ち着くな 白衣
うん？
Lab coats always calm me down.
ガシっと！
あっ…！
Perfect!
I was right...
俺の目に狂いはなかった
お前は最高だ
You're perfect.
な なによ 急に 気持ち悪い…
Wh-What's wrong?
You're creeping me out.
白衣！ やはり 研究機関において
白衣こそがユニホーム！
A lab coat!
In a research organization,
a lab coat is a uniform!
ダルも まゆりも 何度 言っても
それが分からないようだが
I keep telling Daru and Mayuri,
but neither of them seems to understand.
お前には 分かっているようだな
But you understand.
さあ 共に手を突っ込んで
立とうではないか！
Now, let's both stand with
our hands in our pockets!
はあ？
早く！
Hurry up!
こ… こう？
そうだ！
L-Like this?
That's right!
これぞ まさに
研究に身を置く者だけが漂わせる
This is a pose of radiant intelligence,
possible only for those
知性と恍惚のポーズ！
who spend their lives in research!
その白衣は
お前に プレゼントしよう
I give that lab coat to you.
２人で 思う存分
分かち合おうではないか
Let us share in the glory together...
フ～ッハッハッハ…！
I really do feel like you're mocking me.
侮辱されているようにしか
思えんぞ…
あっ…
You hungry?
腹が減ったのか？
Shut up.
うるさいな
お昼から 何も食べてないのよ
I haven't eaten since lunch.
いいだろう
今日の俺は 気分がいい
Very well.
I'm in a good mood today.
おいしく頂け
本気か？
Enjoy. I demand it.
Seriously?
不満か？
当たり前でしょ！
You're dissatisfied?
Of course!
他に 何かないの？
Isn't there anything else?
買い置きのカップめんならあるが
I've got some cup ramen I bought.
いらないというのか？
やはり アメリカ育ちは…
But I imagine you wouldn't want it,
as someone raised in America...
カップめん…
Cup ramen?
カップめん もらうわ
I'll have some cup ramen.
味は 何があるの？
What flavors?
Soy sauce and salt!
しょうゆと塩だ！
塩味 それと フォークも
I'll have the salt flavor.
And a fork.
早くしないと
時間切れで負けになるわよ
If you don't hurry,
time will expire, and you'll lose.
ぐっ…
諦めたら？
Why not give up?
That's a virus card at the end, isn't it?
どうせ その端にあるのが
ウィルスカードでしょ バレバレよ
I can tell.
ふんっ
そう思うなら そう思えばいい
You may think that if you like.
So I'll just put this here.
じゃあ 私は
これを ここに置いて…
Okay, riichi.
はい リーチ
ほう… 助手は
ドクトルペッパーがいける口か？
You like Dr Pepper, assistant?
うん？ あっ…
本場で ７年 過ごしてきたからな
I spent seven years in America, after all.
お前とは
いい飲み友達になれそうだ
I'd love to drink with you sometime...
残念だけど 私 未成年だから
Unfortunately, I'm a minor.
ドクペを飲みかわす友達
という意味だ
I meant someone to drink Dr Pepper with.
それ限定？
Just that?
Just that exactly.
だからこそ 意味があるのだ
We can share in the intellectual
experience that is Dr Pepper...
共に 知的飲料である
ドクペへの思いを共有し…
とか言いながら
Stop trying to look at my card,
while you're saying that.
こっそり 私のカード
めくろうとするの やめてくれる？
はい 私の勝ち
なっ！
All right, I win.
正直 言って 岡部は
To be honest,
you're not that good at taking
the strategic view, Okabe.
大局的視点に欠けていると
言わざるを得ないわね
You only consider your own strategy,
考えているのは
いつも 自分の作戦のことだけ
相手が どう考えているとか
ワナがあるかもなんて
never thinking about your opponent's plan,
or whether something is a trap...
全く 考えてない…
待て！
Wait!
何よ？
What?
What did you say?
今 何と言った？
I said you're not good at
taking the strategic view.
大局的視点に欠けていると
言ったのは 事実でしょ…
I-It's true, isn't it?
うっ…！
Before that!
その前だ ｢岡部｣と言ったな？
You said Okabe, right?
だ だから 何よ？
So what?
確かに
私は あんたより年下だけど
I'm younger than you, but for someone
敬意を表さない相手には…
I'm not showing respect for...
No!
違～う！
ああっ！
俺は 鳳凰院だ！
I am Hououin!
何度 言えば 分かるのだ
クリスティーナ！
How many times must I tell you, Christina?
以後 鳳凰院
From now on, remember to call me Hououin!
Or Kyouma...
もしくは 凶真と呼ぶように
あっ…
うん？ 泣いているのか？
Are you crying?
泣いてないわよ！
I'm not crying!
I definitely wasn't terrified by a guy
男の人に 怖い顔で迫られて
恐怖を感じたとか
screaming in my face,
その後 ほっとして 涙が出たとか
そういうこと 全然ないし！
so I definitely didn't start
crying from relief afterwards!
That's not what happened!
Daru, why is my assistant crying?
ダル
助手は なんで 泣いているのだ？
今 本人が 全部 説明したわけだが
She just told you.
And I put this here... Huh?
ええと… これを こうし… あら？
うん？ で こいつが
ここにあるってことは…
If this goes here, then this goes here...
ああ これ こうだ
助手よ
Assistant.
I'm not your assistant, but what?
助手じゃないが 何？
Why don't you head back
to the hotel for the night?
今晩は
一度 ホテルに戻ったら どうだ？
近いのだろ？
It's close, isn't it?
Don't worry.
ご心配なく
朝になってダメだったら帰るわ
If it doesn't work by morning, I'll head back.
家族に連絡しなくていいのか？
You don't need to talk to your family?
My mom's in America,
母は アメリカ
父とは ７年 会ってない
and I haven't spoken to my dad in seven years.
よって 連絡の必要なし
So I don't have anyone to contact.
放とう天才変態少女というわけか
A prodigal perverted genius girl, then.
変なもの 付け足していくな
Stop making it even weirder.
キタ…
あっ！
Got it!
キター！
やったのか？
You did it?
Mission complete second!
ミッションコンプリート セカンド
So what's the result?
それで 結果は？
ああ まだ 何も見てないよ
I haven't seen anything yet.
But I got the Z-program...
ただ Ｚプログラムは出てきて…
It says 1973?
｢1973年｣と書いてあるのか？
そうね
Yeah...
ＳＥＲＮの設立は？
1954年
When was SERN founded?
1954.
IBN5100が つくられたのは？
When was the IBN 5100 made?
1975.
1975年
SERN gave the IBN 5100
この計画のために ＳＥＲＮは
a special programming language,
just for this plan?
IBN5100に 特殊な
プログラム言語を実装させた
That's going too far.
強引にも程がある
But it's possible.
しかし 可能性はある
Once we read this report, we'll know, right?
それは このレポートを読めば
はっきりするでしょ
きっと 陰謀なんか 全く関係ない
I'm sure its just an old particle physics report,
当時の素粒子のレポートか
何かでしょうから
and nothing to do with conspiracy theories.
A JPEG? Seriously? Screw you!
ああ～！ ＪＰＥＧかよ！
ふざけんな コピペできねえじゃん
I can't copy/paste that!
It's not in French?
フランス語じゃないんだ？
Um, "Time Control and
Its Destruction of History"...
ええと… ｢時空の支配と
それに基づく 歴史の破壊｣
Oh, yeah. Miss Makise can read English.
そっか 牧瀬氏 英語 読めるんか
Well done, assistant!
でかした 助手！
お前が アメリカに行ったのも
Everything you did in America
was for this moment!
全て
今日 この時のためだったのだな
そんなわけあるか
The hell it was.
Let's see...
えっと… ｢言いかえれば
This, in turn, enables a utopia
heading from the past to the future.
過去から未来までを含む
理想郷の実現
The realization of this will be
SERN's reason for existence in the 21st century.
それは 21世紀に向けての
ＳＥＲＮの存在意義となるだろう｣
A utopia...
理想郷… ディストピア！
Dystopia!
No way!
そんなわけない！
前口上はいいから 本文を見せて
Anyway, show me the rest.
って言われても…
I can try, I guess.
ええと ｢本実験は機密事項のため｣
ああ… じゃなくて…
Hmm... For security reasons, this experiment...
That's not it.
｢プログラム従事者における｣…
でもなくて
Those engaged by the program...
No, that's not it, either.
あった ｢Ｚプログラムでは
高エネルギーの陽子衝突を用いた
Got it.
The Z-program will experiment
with the possibility of
transference through space-time,
via high-energy proton collision...
時空転移実験を行う｣…
時空転移…？
Space-time travel...
タイムトラベルではないか！
They're talking about time travel!
ウソ！
ウソではない！
No way!
It's true!
やはり ＳＥＲＮは 40年も前から
I knew it! SERN's been investigating
time travel for forty years!
タイムトラベルについて
研究を行ってきたのだ！
待って！ 結論を出すのは早すぎる
Wait!
It's too early to say that.
Program Stage One:
｢プログラム 第１段階
Construction and implementation
of the Large Hadron.
大型ハドロンの建設
および 実用化
プログラム 第２段階
Program Stage Two:
Implementation and tuning of the lifter.
リフターの実用化 および 調整｣
リフター？ 何だ？
Lifter? What's that?
It was on the news a while back, remember?
昔 ちょっとだけ
話題になったやつっしょ？
The thing they called an ionocraft.
イオンクラフトとかって
呼ばれていたやつ
えっと…
浮いてる？
It's floating?
アルミに高電圧をかけると起きる
現象みたいだけど…
Supposedly, the phenomenon occurs when
you run a high voltage through aluminum.
Does that have anything to do
with a time machine?
それが
タイムマシンに関係あるのか？
I don't know, but that's what it says.
分からないけど
ここでは そう書かれているわね
In other words, they'll use
つまり ブラックホールと
リフターの力を利用する
a black hole's power and the lifter.
その先は？
What else does it say?
Program Stage Three: Animal experiments.
｢プログラム 第３段階 動物実験
プログラム 第４段階｣…
Program Stage Four...
あっ！
どうした？
What's wrong?
｢人体実験｣
Human experiments.
｢Human is Dead,mismatch｣
"Human is dead, mismatch."
What's that?
何？
Part of an e-mail we found when we hacked in.
ハッキングしたときに出ていた
メールの一部だ
確か その先は…
Didn't the rest of it say...
"The details are in Jellyman's report."
｢詳細は
ゼリーマンズレポートを参照｣
Daru, can you find that report?
ダル それを見ることはできるか？
I think so, but...
できるとは思うけど… マズくね？
Isn't it a bad idea?
If this is real, it's top-secret stuff!
これ 事実だとしたら
マジ 国家機密級だって
After all this, you're scared?
ここまで来て ビビってるの？
考えてみろ 相手はＳＥＲＮ
Think about it.
We're up against SERN.
And the report's a top-secret thing,
レポートは
40年以上も隠されてきた
written forty years ago.
トップシークレットだぞ
じゃあ 見ないつもり？
Then you're going to ignore it?
フッ…
お前は もう帰れ
えっ？
You go home.
If you learn any more of this,
ここから先を知ったら
危険にさらされる可能性がある
it might put you in danger.
You're a genius, with a
bright future ahead of you.
お前は
将来を有望視された天才だろ
Are you worried about me?
もしかして
心配してくれているの？
Of course I am!
当たり前だ！ お前は…
You... You're my assistant.
俺の助手なのだからな
Thanks.
そりゃ どうも でも帰らないわよ
But I'm not going home.
このままじゃ
気になって 眠れないから
I'll be too bothered by this to sleep.
後悔しないな？
しない
You won't regret it, will you?
I won't.
What about you, Daru?
ダルは どうする？
まっ 僕 スーパーハッカーだし
I'm a super hacker.
見たところで 足が付くような
ヘマはしないっつうか
I wouldn't screw up so bad, they could
catch us, just by looking at it.
Very well.
分かった では…
Then we will now begin our analysis
これより ゼリーマンズレポートの
解析に入る
of the Jellyman's report!
Furthermore, this operation's name will be
なお 以降 本作戦の名称を
｢レーギャルンの筐｣とする！
Laegjarn's Chest!
Why Norse mythology?
なんで 北欧神話？
And why does it even need
an operation name at all?
っつうか そもそも
作戦名とか言いだしちゃうのって
ダル 作戦開始だ！
Daru, begin the operation!
Right.
へいへい
Is this it?
これか？
うん 全部で ファイルは14個ある
There are fourteen files, total.
I'll pick one at random.
適当に開いてみるお
｢ゼリーマンズレポート10
Jellyman's Report 10.
Subject: James McCarthy.
被験者 ジェームス･マッカーシー
出身 アメリカ
American.
実験日 2005年１月28日
Experiment Date 01/28/2005.
Z-Program 4 Experiment Result:
Ｚプログラム４ 実験結果
Human is dead, mismatch.
Human is Dead,mismatch｣
また それ？
That again?
It is believed he could not
survive infinite compression,
超重力による無限圧縮
および カー･ブラックホール内の
via supergravity, nor passing through the
singularity inside the Kerr black hole.
特異点通過に
耐えられなかったと思われる
新聞か？
そうみたいね… あっ 日付！
A newspaper article?
Looks like it.
Look at the date!
April 3, 1921.
｢1921年４月３日｣
A man was found dead,
｢ニューヨーク 14丁目にて
ビルの壁面に埋もれるようにして
死んでいる男が発見された
on 14th Avenue, in New York, buried inside a wall.
身元不明の男性の死体は
The body of this unidentified man
was found to be soft, like jelly...
全身が
ブヨブヨのゼリー状になっていた｣
ああ…
What is this?
なんだ これ…
完全ではないにしろ
It means that, even if it isn't complete,
they've succeeded in time travel?
タイムトラベルに
成功してるってこと？
｢レポート８ 被験者 リンダ･ヒル
出身 イギリス
Report 8.
Subject: Linda Hill.
British.
Ｚプログラム４
Z-Program 4.
実験日 2004年２月15日
Experiment Date 02/15/2004.
Experiment Result: Human is dead,
実験結果
Human is Dead,mismatch｣
mismatch.
October 2, 1972.
｢1972年10月２日
インド タミル･ナードゥ州
The body of a woman was found
ダルマプリの路上で
in a jelly-like state, on a road
in Dharmapuri, Tamil Nadu, India.
ゼリー状になった
女性の遺体を発見｣
It was believed to have been
｢放置された後で
車にひかれた跡があり
hit by a car, after being abandoned, destroying the bottom half.
下半身は損壊｣
こっちは？
What about this one?
Report 7.
｢レポート７
被験者 ミハエル･ラング
Subject: Michael Lang.
出身 ドイツ Ｚプログラム４
German.
Z-Program 4.
Experiment Result: Human is dead, mismatch.
実験結果
Human is Dead,mismatch｣
ふん… うん？ 日本の新聞か？
A Japanese newspaper?
うん ｢1936年５月24日
May 24, 1936.
A body is discovered at the
foot of Mt. Hiei, in Kyoto.
京都 比叡山山麓で遺体発見さる｣
Fourteen of these?
これが 14人分…
Want to keep looking?
まだ 見る？
いや もう十分だ
No, that's enough.
うっ… オ オカリン
Okarin...
I'm going to buy something to drink.
飲み物 買ってくる
相当 ショックだったみたいね
He seems pretty shocked.
Yeah.
はあ… けど
どうして ゼリー状になるん？
But why do they turn to jelly?
From the data I've seen,
これまでのデータから推測するに
I believe SERN is focusing their time travel
ＳＥＲＮは
カー･ブラックホールを使って
research on the use of Kerr black holes.
タイムトラベルの技術を
開発している
That would mean
だとすると
10のマイナス24乗キロの質量を
they're cramming 10^-21 grams into
a space of 10^-19 meters,
and sending it to the past.
10のマイナス19乗ｍの所に
押し込んで 過去に送るわけ
It would be like trying to fit
this sponge through this hole.
この穴に このスポンジを
通そうとするようなものよ
Therefore,
だから…
the contents become empty.
中身がスカスカになる
So, it's really tight.
つまり すごく狭いってこと？
そう すごく狭いところに
無理やり ねじ込む
Yes.
They're forcing something into a really tight spot.
That explanation is too nasty, you know.
その説明はエロすぎだろ 常考
はあ？ 何がエロすぎ…
What's nasty...
はっ？ 橋田のHENTAI！
Daru, you pervert!
I think you have a
considerable imagination yourself.
そういう牧瀬氏も かなりの妄想力
Don't compare me to you.
一緒にすんな
What are you going to do?
どうするつもり？
Don't just stand there.
黙ってないでよ
ショックなのは分かる
I know it's a shock.
But now that we know this,
けど 知ってしまった以上
何らかの結論は出さなきゃ
we have to reach some conclusion.
フフフフ… フハハハ…
Okabe?
岡部？
フ～ッハッハッハ…
Conclusion?
結論？ 決まっているだろう
はっ？
What other conclusion could there be?
Huh?
We've got Future Gadget #8,
こっちには 未来ガジェット８号
電話レンジ(仮)があるのだ
the Phone Microwave (name subject to change).
We'll complete a perfect
time machine, ahead of SERN!
先に
完璧なタイムマシンをつくりだし
ＳＥＲＮを出し抜く！
And change the world's ruling structure!
そして 世界の支配構造を
つくり替えるのだ！
ハハハハ…
フ～ッハッハッハ…！
You're nuts, you know that?
つきあってらんない
人工衛星の墜落から
５日が経過した
秋葉原のラジ館前です
今日も 朝から 大勢の人が
見物に詰めかけていますが
放置されたままの人工衛星は
依然として 国籍等不明のまま
撤去のめどは立っておりません